woolworthsmoney.com.au 2018-03-19

# Privacy Policy - Woolworths Cards

### ABOUT THIS STATEMENT

This is a privacy disclosure statement regarding your personal information related to Woolworths Money products and services. The following is to help you understand expressions used in this statement:

**Woolworths Money Provider  **means Woolworths, Macquarie, AIA, ANZ and any other supplier of Woolworths Money Products.

**Woolworths Money Products**  means products and services supplied under or by reference to the Woolworths Money trade mark.

**WM personal information**  means personal information collected from or about you related to Woolworths Money Products, for example as a result of your application for a Woolworths Money Product .

**Woolworths**  means Woolworths Group Limited ABN 88 000 014 675 and its related bodies corporate.

**Macquarie**  means Macquarie Bank Limited ABN 46 008 583 542 AFSL and Australian credit licence number 237502 and its related bodies corporate.

**AIA**  means American International Assurance Company (Australia) Limited ABN 79 004 837 861 and its related bodies corporate.

**ANZ  **means Australia and New Zealand Banking Group Limited ACN 005 357 522 AFSL 234527.

This statement concerns only WM personal information. Application forms for Woolworths Money Products contain terms and conditions regarding WM personal information. Because those terms and conditions provide for certain consents, if you agree to them they will impact on how Woolworths Money Providers use and disclose your personal information. You can view the application form terms and conditions on-line at, woolworthsmoney.com.au or, obtain a copy of the application form by contacting the Woolworths Money Call Centre on 1300 10 1234 or by writing to the Woolworths Money Privacy Officer at the address set out below. This statement should be read with the terms and conditions on those application forms.

Woolworths Money Providers may collect personal information from or about you which is not WM personal information. For example, you may be a client of Macquarie's financial planning services, a Woolworth's lay-by customer or you may have a bank account with ANZ, and for those relationships, Macquarie, Woolworths or ANZ collects personal information from you. This statement does not relate to that other information. For privacy information about that other personal information, see the relevant provider's privacy information at its website (for example [www.woolworthsgroup.com.au;](https://www.woolworthsgroup.com.au/)[ ](http://www.woolworthslimited.com.au/)[www.macquarie.com.au;](http://www.macquarie.com.au/) [www.aia.com.au;](http://www.aia.com.au/) [www.anz.com.au](http://www.anz.com.au/)) or by contacting the provider directly.

Australian privacy law requires Woolworths Money Providers to be open about their general practices relating to the management of personal information. They must let people know, generally, what sort of information they hold, for what purposes and how they collect, hold, use and disclose that information. Woolworths Money Providers' privacy policies are at the websites referred to above (for example [www.woolworthsgroup.com.au](https://www.woolworthsgroup.com.au/)[; ](https://www.woolworthsgroup.com.au/)[www.macquarie.com.au;](http://www.macquarie.com.au/) [www.aia.com.au;](http://www.aia.com.au/) [www.anz.com.au](http://www.anz.com.au/)) or by contacting the provider directly.

### MATTERS OF WHICH YOU SHOULD BE AWARE REGARDING YOUR WM PERSONAL INFORMAITON

### Who is the organisation that collects WM personal information from you?

The organisation that collects WM personal information from you will be one of the Woolworths Money Providers depending on the Woolworths Money Product. For more information please read the terms and conditions on the relevant application form. For example, the WM personal information in relation to the Woolworths Money Credit Card is collected by Macquarie, the issuer of the Woolworths Money Product. Woolworths might also be involved in the collection of some personal information from you relevant to the Woolworths Money Product. For example, the WM personal information in relation to Woolworths Money prepaid cards is collected by Woolworths and may be shared with ANZ or Macquarie.

### For what purpose is your WM personal information collected?

Your WM personal information can be used and disclosed by Woolworths Money Providers and their contractors:

  * To assess and process applications for an Woolworths Money Product;
  * For any purpose related to the provision of Woolworths Money Products to you and to carry out any associated payments, administration and account services; 
  * To assess any application you make for a product or service other than a Woolworths Money Product; 
  * To promote, facilitate and manage the provision of any Woolworths Money Product to you; 
  * To maintain, administer and update any other product or service a Woolworths Money Provider provides to you; 
  * To link any other product or service, such as your Everyday RewardsTM card, to your Woolworths Money Product;
  * For planning, product development and research purposes and to seek your feedback on the products and services offered by Woolworths Money Providers; 
  * To identify and develop products or services that may interest you and to market them to you (unless you ask the Woolworths Money Provider not to do this); 
  * To analyse transaction details and transaction history to build peer / individual group profiling to enable a Woolworths Money Provider to compare your account and shopping behaviour with your peer groups; 
  * To detect fraud or money laundering activities or terrorist finance activities and comply with other legislative requirements; 
  * To facilitate any transactions entered into between you and a Woolworths Money Provider or any transactions entered into or performed by a Woolworths Money Provider at your or any Authorised Signatory's request and for or on your or any Authorised Signatory's behalf. An Authorised Signatory is any additional signatory or beneficiary nominated by you for a Woolworths Money Product; 
  * To identify you or establish your tax status under any Australian or foreign legislation, regulation or treaty or pursuant to an agreement with any tax authority; 
  * As required by relevant laws, regulations, codes of practice and external payment systems; If by virtue of your employment, you are entitled to any additional benefits or entitlement relating to your Woolworths Money Products, to verify from time to time the status of your employment.

### To whom does the Woolworths Money Provider usually disclose information of the same kind as your WM personal information?

Woolworths Money Providers usually disclose the type of information comprising WM personal information to the following:

  * Another Woolworths Money Provider (each Woolworths Money Provider's Privacy Policy will tell you more about the types of disclosures. Details of where to find the Privacy Policies are set out above);
  * Service providers engaged to do something on their behalf;
  * Any person to whom disclosure is necessary to execute your instructions;
  * Any person through whom you have applied, or by whom you are introduced to a Woolworths Money Provider;
  * Any additional signatory or beneficiary nominated by you for an Woolworths Money Product;
  * Any financial institution to facilitate your transactions involving Woolworths Money Products (including via ATMs, internet banking and BPAY®, registered to BPAY Ltd ABN 69 079 137 518 );
  * Any payment systems operators and participants in the payment system (including payment organisations and merchants);
  * In (respect of credit information) credit reporting agencies; any third party (such as your employer/accountant) to check that information given is correct; another credit provider from which they may seek information, from whom you may seek credit, or to whom they may assign your Woolworths Money Products;
  * Debt collection agencies;
  * Any insurer, insurance broker or agent from whom or through whom any insurance policy is taken out, or to be taken out, in connection with any Woolworths Money Product;
  * Where they decide to sell or merge any aspect of their business, any person considering purchasing or who purchases, funds or manages that business or an interest in your Woolworths Money Products and their advisers;
  * Regulators and law enforcement agencies such as under court orders, taxation, social security or anti-money laundering and terrorist financing laws or statutory notices and others in respect of whom you have given your consent.

### Is there any law that requires your particular WM personal information to be collected?

You may decide not to provide a Woolworths Money Provider with any WM personal information. If you decide to apply for a Woolworths Money Product, some of the personal information for which you will be asked is permitted or required by law in order for the Woolworths Money Provider to process the application. Examples of relevant laws are financial transaction reporting, anti-money laundering, taxation, finance, credit and insurance laws. If you would like more information about this aspect, you may direct your query to the Privacy Officer whose details are given below.

### What are the main consequences (if any) if all or part of your WM personal information is not provided?

You are not required to provide personal information in relation to all Woolworths Money products. For example, you can purchase the Woolworths Money Prepaid MasterCard® without making an application.

However, if an application is required to obtain a particular Woolworths Money Product, the main consequence of not providing your WM personal information is that your application will not be accepted.

### How can you make contact with a Woolworths Money Privacy Officer?

You can contact a Woolworths Money Privacy Officer at the following:

Phone: 1300 908 631 (9am - 5pm Monday to Friday)

Email: [privacy@woolworths.com.au](mailto:privacy@woolworths.com.au)

Or by writing to:

The Privacy Officer,

Woolworths Money, Woolworths Group Limited

PO Box 8000

Baulkham Hills NSW 2153

### How can you enquire about, access and correct your personal information?

We will provide you with access to any of your personal information we hold (except in limited circumstances recognised by law). If you wish to access your personal information or have an enquiry about privacy, please contact our Privacy Officer at one of the above contact points.

Before we provide you with access to your personal information we may require some proof of identity. We may charge a reasonable fee for giving access to your personal information if your request requires substantial effort on our part.

If you need to correct your personal information, please contact our Privacy Officer at one of the above contact points.

### How can you complain about our management of personal information?

If you wish to complain about a breach of the privacy rules that bind us, you may contact our Privacy Officer at one of the above contact points. We may ask you to put your complaint in writing and to provide details about it.

We may discuss your complaint with our personnel and our service providers and others as appropriate.

Our Privacy Officer will investigate the matter and attempt to resolve it in a timely way. Our Privacy Officer will inform you in writing about the outcome of the investigation. If our Privacy Officer does not resolve your complaint to your satisfaction and no other complaint resolution procedures are agreed or required by law, our Privacy Officer will inform you that your complaint may be referred to the Privacy Commissioner for further investigation and will provide you with the Commissioner's contact details.
